Guide to the George G. Phelps Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George G. Phelps Family papers
1838-1927
MS 17
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
Correspondence and business papers of George G. Phelps, farmer and businessman, and other members of the Phelps family of Hebron, Meriden and Wallingford, Connecticut.
Phelps, George G.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from George L. Gaines, Jr., in 1942.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence. II. General Subject Files.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers of George G. Phelps and other members of the Phelps Family of Hebron, Meriden and Wallingford, Connecticut, consist primarily of family letters, business letters and papers for the period 1838-1928. Most of the correspondence is concentrated in the period 1855-1859 and concerns Mr. Phelps' farm in Manchester, various real estate interests in Hebron, Grand Lodge matters and proceedings on financial notes. The 173 piece collection was purchased from George L. Gaines, Jr., in 1942, and is of limited historical interest, providing some information on the business of farming in Connecticut in the mid-nineteenth century and on the local history of the towns discussed in the letters.
Agriculture -- Connecticut; Agriculture; Families; Connecticut; Manchester (Conn.); Farmers; Phelps, George G.; Phelps family
- Correspondence, 1854-1859, 1926-1927; Series I; 3" 1/2 Box
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence contains family and business letters written to George G. Phelps, Mary Page Phelps, Elizabeth Phelps, Harriet C. Phelps, and Emma K. Foskett. The letters are arranged alphabetically by name of author for each member of the family.
  Topics covered in letters include George G. Phelps' farm in Wallingford, real estate interests and Grand Lodge matters.
  - Letters to George G. Phelps
    - Bissel, [P?], 1856 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bishop, Alfred, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bliss, B.S., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Campbell, James, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Elliot, George, 1855-1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fitch, Henry H., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fitch, S.S., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gilbert, Leyton R., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gillet, N., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gillett, G., 1858-1859 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hanks, F.F., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Harris, S.H., 1855-1857 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hyde, A.P., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Jones, Amos, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lewis, William, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Page, Ebenezer B., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Page, Jonathan G., 1855-1857 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Parker, Phiny, 1854-1859, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Phelps, Alfred M., 1855-1858 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Phelps, Elizabeth, 1855-1858 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Phelps, George G., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Phelps, Mary, 1858-1859, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Root, Austin, 1856-1858 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Root, Marvia, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letters to Mary Page Phelps
    - Brown, S.L., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Fitch, Dr. S.S., 1855 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hanks, Abby, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Hanks, C.F., 1858 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Hanks, E.P., 1854 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hanson, D.D., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Harris, Eliz. Mary, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Page, I., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Phelps, Harriet C., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Root, Marvia, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Phelps
    - Parker, Phiny, 1857, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Phelps, Harriet C., 1856, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Unknown sender, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letters to Harriet C. Phelps
    - Buck, Dorliski, E., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Parker, Andrew, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Parker, Phiny, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Tuttle, A.E., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Ellen (her cousin), 1856 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters to Emma K. Foskett
    - Seymour, George N., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- General subject file, 1838-1888; Series II; 3" 1/2 Box
  This series includes appointment certificates, minutes, Grand Lodge communications, receipts and printed material.
  - Appointment Certificates, 1850, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1838, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Grand Lodge of Connecticut Communications, 1851-1852, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Receipts, 1855-1857 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Advertisement Leaflets, 1852, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Prayer Meeting Schedule, Spring, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Newspaper Clipping about Escaped Slave Family, February 28, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Calling Card, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Personal Note, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)